<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>featured on Yukonwoodcraft - Cabinet making &amp; custom furniture</title><link>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/categories/featured/</link><description>Recent content in featured on Yukonwoodcraft - Cabinet making &amp; custom furniture</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 12:20:54 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/categories/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Armoire Set</title><link>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/19-hotel-armoire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 12:20:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/19-hotel-armoire/</guid><description>For this client a set of 4 matching armoires was created. The idea was to create a airy piece of furniture fitting a modern natural looking space. The pieces were created from fir and birch wood to match the aesthetic of the rest of the interior.</description></item><item><title>Feature Shelves</title><link>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/18-feature-shelves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 12:20:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/18-feature-shelves/</guid><description>This project entailed creating a shelf feature that wrapped around most of the exterior walls of an office. I worked closely with the client to come up with a design. The idea was to have something that is a visual feature while still being light and unobtrusive. The shelves also needed to match the existing maple furniture that was already in place. Mounting was done with a french cleat system which allows to hide the mounting hardware completely.</description></item><item><title>Maple Standing Desks</title><link>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/17-standing-desks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 12:20:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/17-standing-desks/</guid><description>For this client 5 standing desks for an office were created. The desks feature solid maple veneer tops. The veneers were cut from solid maple blanks to match the grain for each desk. The table tops were mounted on height adjustable bases which makes it possible to use the desk in a standing as well as sitting position.</description></item><item><title>Book Shelf</title><link>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/15-book-shelf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:20:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/15-book-shelf/</guid><description>This client requested a book shelf that complemented the wood accents and design of their house. The shelf was made from fir wood and finished with an natural wax/oil finish.</description></item><item><title>Couch Table</title><link>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/14-couch-table/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:20:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/14-couch-table/</guid><description>For this project a multi-mode couch table was designed and built. The table is made from solid birch wood. The tapered legs are attached via hand cut joinery. The table can be used in 2 different ways. First in a regular horizontal way and secondly in a vertical position where the legs slide under the couch offering a surface to place i.e. drinks.</description></item><item><title>Blanket Chest</title><link>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/13-blanket-chest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:20:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.yukonwoodcraft.ca/portfolio/13-blanket-chest/</guid><description>For this client a fir blanket chest was designed and fabricated. The chest features box joinery and a simple modern design. A oil/wax finish has been applied to preserve the natural wood look.</description></item></channel></rss>